Hi, now one more recurrence relation I'll solve I have not written any algorithm directly
안녕하세요, 이제 하나의 재귀 관계를 더 풀어보겠습니다. 알고리즘을 직접 작성하지 않았고
I have taken a recurrence relation and this is dividing function tn is divided. I'll solve this using
재귀 관계를 가져왔습니다. 이 함수 tn은 나누어집니다. 이것을
recursion tree method
재귀 트리 방법으로 풀어보겠습니다.
See tn
tn을 보세요.
There are two steps in this one
여기에는 두 단계가 있습니다.
tn by 2 and
tn을 2로 나누고
n
n
n is the time taken in this step plus the time taken here also
이 단계에서 걸리는 시간과 여기서도 걸리는 시간을 더합니다.
Then what this will be this will be taking n by 2 time and also it will be tn by 2 square
그러면 이것은 n을 2로 나눈 시간과 tn을 2의 제곱으로 나눈 시간이 됩니다.
Then what this will be it will be taking n by 2 square time
그러면 이것은 n을 2의 제곱으로 나눈 시간이 됩니다.
and
그리고
tn by 2 cube
tn을 2의 세제곱으로 나눕니다.
This way I'll be go on reducing
이렇게 계속 줄여나갈 것입니다.
I'll be go on reducing. How long how long and for k times
계속 줄여나갈 것입니다. 얼마나 오래, k번 동안
n by 2 power k times. I'll repeat until here
n을 2의 k제곱으로 나눌 때까지 반복합니다.
Then when it is n by 2 power k
그런 다음 n을 2의 k제곱으로 나눌 때
I assume that this has became 1 because what is the smaller value I have n equal to 1
이것이 1이 되었다고 가정합니다. 왜냐하면 가장 작은 값이 n=1이기 때문입니다.
So I assume that I have reduced it up to 1
그래서 1까지 줄였다고 가정합니다.
Now what this will be
이제 이것은 무엇일까요
If I take these times and add them in each step
이 시간을 각 단계에서 더하면
So it will be n and it is n by 2
n이 되고 n을 2로 나눈 것이 됩니다.
It's n by 2 square and goes on to n by 2 power k
n을 2의 제곱으로 나눈 것이 되고 계속해서 n을 2의 k제곱으로 나눕니다.
Right see the last step will be n by 2 power k, right
마지막 단계는 n을 2의 k제곱으로 나누는 것입니다.
See, this is n cube and this is n square
이것은 n의 세제곱이고 이것은 n의 제곱입니다.
So this will be last will be 2 power k minus 1
그래서 마지막은 2의 k-1제곱이 됩니다.
So for this some something will be there some function will be there here and it will be n by 2 power
여기에 어떤 함수가 있을 것이고 n을 2의 k-1제곱으로 나누는 것이 있습니다.
k minus 1 and when it is n by 2 power k it stops, so
그리고 n을 2의 k제곱으로 나누면 멈춥니다.
Approximately I am taking it till n by 2 power k or k minus 1 also I can take it
대략적으로 n을 2의 k제곱 또는 k-1제곱까지 가져갑니다.
Now, let me add all these
이제 이것들을 모두 더해봅시다.
To get the answer. So this is n plus n by 2 plus n by 2 square
답을 얻기 위해서요. 그래서 이것은 n 더하기 n을 2로 나눈 것 더하기 n을 2의 제곱으로 나눈 것입니다.
plus n by 2 cube
플러스 n 나누기 2의 세제곱
Plus goes on to n by 2 power k
플러스는 n 나누기 2의 k제곱까지 계속됩니다.
This will be Tn
이것은 Tn이 될 것입니다.
What this is equal to n common
이것은 n 공통으로 무엇과 같습니까?
1 plus 1 by 2 plus 1 by 2 square plus 1 by 2 cube plus goes on to
1 플러스 1 나누기 2 플러스 1 나누기 2의 제곱 플러스 1 나누기 2의 세제곱 플러스 계속해서
1 by 2 power k
1 나누기 2의 k제곱까지
This is n sigma
이것은 n 시그마입니다.
1 by 2 power i, i takes the values from 0 to k
1 나누기 2의 i제곱, i는 0부터 k까지의 값을 가집니다.
What is this equal to this will be equal to 1?
이것은 무엇과 같습니까? 이것은 1과 같을 것입니다.
Remember this this will be equal to 1 so this is n into 1 so Tn answer is n
기억하세요, 이것은 1과 같으므로 이것은 n 곱하기 1입니다. 그래서 Tn의 답은 n입니다.
So this is big O of n or theta of n anything you can say for explanation
그래서 이것은 빅 오 표기법(Big O notation)으로 n 또는 세타 표기법(Theta notation)으로 n입니다. 설명을 위해
I'll take one circle
하나의 원을 가져보겠습니다.
and
그리고
This is half of a circle
이것은 원의 절반입니다.
this is
이것은
1 4th of a circle
원의 1/4입니다.
This is 1 8th of a circle
이것은 원의 1/8입니다.
This is 1 16th of a circle if I continue goes on so it means 1 by 2 plus
이것은 원의 1/16입니다. 계속하면 1 나누기 2 플러스
1 by 2 square plus
1 나누기 2의 제곱 플러스
1 by 2 cube plus 1 by 2 power 4 plus goes on up to
1 나누기 2의 세제곱 플러스 1 나누기 2의 4제곱 플러스 계속해서
Infinity if I add all these pieces it is equal to one circle is one circle
무한대까지 이 모든 조각을 더하면 하나의 원과 같습니다.
Half 1 4th 1 8 and all if you add them up to infinity is 1 so this is
절반, 1/4, 1/8 등을 무한대까지 더하면 1이 됩니다. 그래서 이것은
Approximately equal to 1 so we round it up to 1 n into 1 so it is order of n
대략 1과 같으므로 1로 반올림합니다. n 곱하기 1이므로 이것은 n의 차수(Order of n)입니다.
So this is one method now next method. I'll use substitution method now using substitution method
이것이 한 가지 방법입니다. 이제 다음 방법으로 대입법(Substitution method)을 사용하겠습니다. 이제 대입법을 사용하여
Tn is equals to
Tn은 다음과 같습니다.
Tn by 2 plus n
Tn 나누기 2 플러스 n
If I use this method also, I will get the same series in the tree
이 방법을 사용해도 트리에서 같은 수열을 얻을 것입니다.
I was getting it vertically and and I was adding it here. I will get it horizontally
세로로 얻고 있었고, 여기서 가로로 더하고 있었습니다.
the same
같은
What is the Tn by 2?
Tn 나누기 2는 무엇입니까?
this will be
이것은
Tn by 2 square plus n by 2 and
Tn 나누기 2 제곱 더하기 n 나누기 2이고
This is n
이것은 n입니다
If I open it
이걸 풀어보면
Tn by 2 square plus n by 2 plus n if this was the first equation
Tn 나누기 2 제곱 더하기 n 나누기 2 더하기 n, 이것이 첫 번째 방정식이라면
Then this is the second equation
이것은 두 번째 방정식입니다
I'm not showing you here how to substitute and get the next expression next equation
여기서 대입해서 다음 표현식, 다음 방정식을 얻는 방법을 보여주지 않겠습니다
Already we have done in previous recurrence relation. Maybe you have watched them
이미 이전의 재귀 관계에서 했습니다. 아마 보셨을 겁니다
Next
다음
If I substitute this further, then this will be Tn by 2 cube plus n
이것을 더 대입하면, 이것은 Tn 나누기 2 세제곱 더하기 n
by 2 square plus n by 2
나누기 2 제곱 더하기 n 나누기 2
Plus n if I continue for k times, so then it will be
더하기 n, k번 반복하면, 그러면 이것은
Tn by 2 power k plus n by 2 power k minus 1
Tn 나누기 2의 k승 더하기 n 나누기 2의 k-1승
plus n by 2 power k minus 2
더하기 n 나누기 2의 k-2승
plus goes on to n by 2 plus n
더하기 계속해서 n 나누기 2 더하기 n
That's it I am getting the same thing what is this equal to this is equal to 1
그게 다입니다. 같은 결과를 얻고 있습니다. 이것은 1과 같습니다
Tn is equals to
Tn은
Tn by 2 power k plus
Tn 나누기 2의 k승 더하기
n by 2 power k minus 1
n 나누기 2의 k-1승
plus goes on to n by 2 square plus n by 2
더하기 계속해서 n 나누기 2 제곱 더하기 n 나누기 2
plus n we assume that
더하기 n, 우리는 가정합니다
n
n
By 2 power k is equals to 1 we say that this we have reached till 1 and equal to 1
나누기 2의 k승은 1과 같다고, 우리는 1에 도달했다고 말합니다
Therefore n equal to 2 power k and k is equals to log n
따라서 n은 2의 k승과 같고, k는 log n입니다
If I substitute this in this recurrence relation
이것을 이 재귀 관계에 대입하면
Then this is a T1 plus n is a common 1 by 2 power k minus 1 plus 1 by 2 power
그러면 이것은 T1 더하기 n은 공통적으로 1 나누기 2의 k-1승 더하기 1 나누기 2의
k minus 2 plus goes on to 1 by 2 plus 1
k-2승 더하기 계속해서 1 나누기 2 더하기 1입니다
Then what is this approximately equal to Tn plus this is 1 plus n
그러면 이것은 대략적으로 Tn 더하기 이것은 1 더하기 n입니다
And this whole thing is 1 and this plus 1 is also there plus 1
그리고 이 전체는 1이고, 이 더하기 1도 있습니다. 더하기 1
So this is 1 plus 2n
그래서 이것은 1 더하기 2n입니다
This is big O of n
이것은 O(n)입니다.
Now the answer is same order of n
이제 답은 n의 동일한 차수입니다.